Martin Kamin Papers
Martin Kamin Papers
- Memorabilia
  - Photographs
    - Identified, portrait photos of actors, dancers, artists including Harry Frank, Kevin Kemble, Langston Hughes, Diego Rivera, Arthur Kallet, Frank Shay, Carlos Chavez; many are signed and inscribed to Kamin (Box 10)
    - Unidenitified, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Printed material
    - Air Courier, Aug-Sep 1945; newsletter of the Air Transport Command, European Division; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Backlog, Jan 1945; newspaper of the North African Ferry Division - Air Transport Control (NAFD-ATC) (Box 11)
    - Book lists, catalogs and lists from booksellers in England, Germany, Italy, Spain, etc. (Box 11)
    - Le Canard Enchaine, 29 May 1946; satirical journal, in French (Box 11)
    - French language, miscellaneous, includes one-sheet flyer about Aguedal (Box 11)
    - The Mid-Ocean Chronicle, newsletter of unidentified military unit; includes printed editions and typescripts (Box 11)
    - Programs, circa 1916-1968; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Scrapbook, clippings (Oversize 7)
    - Visa and passport applications (Box 11)
    - Wedding announcement calling card and printing plate (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 11)
- Photographs
  - Albums, individual dancers, dance companies, photos of performances, publicity photo-cards, a few non-dance-related items
    - [Album I], 1920-1948; includes a few original photographs but most are reproductions; majority are of Ruth St. Denis, Ted Shawn, the Denishawn dancers (Oversize 5)
    - [Album II], undated; most are printed cards with captions; album is in very poor condition (Oversize 5)
    - [Album III], undated; most are printed cards with captions (Oversize 5)
  - Ballet companies
    - Adolf Bolm Ballet (Box 12)
      See also Dancers: Bolm, Adolf.
    - Australia (Box 12)
    - Ballet Intime (Box 12)
    - Ballet Rambert (Box 12)
    - Ballet Russe, 1931-1956 (Box 12)
    - Ballet Theatre at McCarter Theatre (Box 12)
    - Denishawn Dancers, 1913-1928 (Box 12)
      See also Albums: [Album I]
    - Denishawn Dancers, 1913 (Oversize B)
    - Diaghilev Ballet (Box 12)
    - Diaghilev Production Staff (Box 12)
    - Martha Graham Dance Company (Box 12)
    - National Ballet of Canada (Box 12)
    - New York City Ballet (Box 12)
    - [Jerome] Robbins (Oversize 6)
    - San Francisco Ballet (Box 12)
    - Ted Shawn and His Men Dancers (Box 12)
    - Various (Box 12)
      Ballets Espagnol, Ballet Imperial, Agnes de Mille Dance Theatre, Bettis[?], Ballet de Champs-Élysées, miscellaneous unidentified
  - Dancers
    - Baronova, Irina (Box 12)
    - Bolm, Adolf (Box 12)
      See also Ballet companies: Adolf Bolm Ballet.
    - Bolm, Adolf (Oversize 6)
    - Danielian, Leon (Box 12)
    - Danilova, Alexandra (Box 12)
    - De Mille, Agnes George (Box 12)
    - Dolin, Anton (Box 12)
    - Duncan, Irma and child dancers (Box 12)
    - Dunham, Katherine (Box 12)
    - Essen, Viola (Box 12)
    - Franklin, Frederic (Box 12)
    - Karsavina, Tamara (Box 13)
    - Kaye, Nora (Box 13)
    - Kovach, Nora (Box 13)
    - Krassovska, Nathalie (Box 13)
    - Lichine, David (Box 13)
    - Markova, Alicia (Box 13)
    - Massine, Leonide (Box 13)
    - Moncion, Francisco (Box 13)
    - Moylan, Mary Ellen (Box 13)
    - Nijinsky, Vaslav (Box 13)
    - Pavlova, Anna (Box 13)
      See also Correspondence: Hudson, Rosario.
    - Primus, Pearl (Box 13)
    - Rabovsky, Istvan (Box 13)
    - St. Denis, Ruth (Box 13)
      See also Photographs: Ballet companies: Denishawn Dancers.
    - Shawn, Ted, See Photographs: Ballet companies: Denishawn Dancers and Photographs: Ballet companies: Ted Shawn and his Men Dancers.
    - Shearer, Moira (Box 13)
    - Slavenska, Mia (Box 13)
    - Tallchief, Maria (Box 13)
    - Tallchief, Maria (Oversize 6)
    - Tcherina, Ludmilla (Box 13)
    - Toumanova, Tamara (Box 13)
      See also Correspondence: Toumanova, Tamara.
    - Young, Loretta (Box 13)
    - Youskevitch, Igor (Box 13)
    - Various, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Various, Anne Eglinsky, Rosella Hightower, Milad Miskovitch, Moscow Ballet School, Nina Novak, Roland Petit (Oversize 6)
    - Various, autographed, some are inscribed to the Kamins, some to other people (Box 13)
    - Unidentified (Box 14)
    - Unidentified (Oversize 6)
  - Dances
    - Bach Cycle (Box 14)
    - The Black Swan (Box 14)
    - Bluebeard (Box 14)
    - Camille (Box 14)
    - Carmen (Box 14)
    - Carmen, Roland Petit, Jean Marie (Oversize 6)
    - Le Combat, Colette Marchand and Milorad Miskovitch (Oversize 6)
    - Coq d'Or (Box 14)
    - Don Quixote (Box 14)
    - Giselle (Box 14)
    - Henry VIII (Box 14)
    - Kabuki, various (Oversize 6)
    - La Malinche, Simon Hoving, Pauline Koner (Oversize 6)
    - Nutcracker (Box 14)
    - Pas de Quatre (Box 14)
    - Pas de Quatre (Oversize 6)
    - Pas de Trois (Box 14)
    - Petrouchka (Box 14)
    - Petrouchka (Oversize 6)
    - Princess Aurora (Box 14)
    - Le Rendezvous Manque (Box 15)
    - Romantic Age (Box 15)
    - Romeo and Juliet (Box 15)
    - Scheherazade (Box 15)
    - La Spectre de la Rose (Box 15)
    - Swan Lake (Box 15)
    - Les Sylphides (Box 15)
    - Sylvia (Box 15)
    - Various, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Unidentified (Box 15)
  - General
    - Conductors, choreographers, etc. (Box 15)
    - Costume design (Box 15)
    - Folk dances (Box 16)
    - Folk dances, Spanish (Box 16)
    - Kamin Dance Bookshop (Box 16)
      See also Printed material: Kamin Dance Bookshop and Subject files: Kamin Dance Bookshop.
    - Movie stills (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - Negatives (Box 16)
- Printed material
  - Concert programs (Box 16)
    See also Programs and souvenir booklets and Miscellaneous folders, below.
  - Dance instruction
    - Catalogs of films and music (Box 16)
    - Dance descriptions, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Examinations (Box 17)
      British Ballet Organization, Federation of Russian Classical Ballet, Imperial Society of Teachers of Dancing Inc., International Dancing Masters Association (IDMA), National Dance Branch, Royal Academy of Dancing
    - Folk dances, 2 folders (Box 17)
      "Jungle dances and their variations" published by the Boy Scouts Assocation; pamphlets in Hebrew and Japanese; "Game animal dances of the Rio Grande Pueblos"; and a set of cards entitled "Rhythmic Activities Series I" by Frances R. Stuart and John S. Ludlam, with English, Danish, American and other folk dances for children
    - Folk dances, 2 folders (Box 18)
      Booklets and sets of activity cards in Russian, Hebrew and Hungarian, as well as booklets in English relating to English, Spanish, and Native American dances
    - Schools (Box 18)
    - Techniques, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Dance notation systems (Box 19)
  - Kamin Dance Book Shop (Box 19)
    See also Photographs: General: Kamin Dance Bookshop and Subject files: Kamin Dance Bookshop.
  - Librettos
    The collection originally contained a number of librettos in various languages. These have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items.
  - Magazine articles, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - News clippings
    - Lifar, Serge, 1932-1938; also includes silver publicity folder with printed photographs (Box 19)
    - Shawn, Ted and Ruth St. Denis, 1921; 1929,; 1947 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928; 1938,; 1940,; 1950,; 1960; in English, Russian, Spanish (Box 19)
  - Pamphlets
    - Miscellaneous (1) (Box 19)
      Topics include Slavic folklore, opera stars, synocopated therapy, the Nijinsky Foundation, Chinese theater, Indonesian dance, Yugoslavian folk dance and music, legal protection for choreography, the Kirby Malzeard Sword Dance, dance and aestheticians, ballet in New Zealand, the London Museum, and UK laws regarding handicapped pupils.
    - Miscellaneous (2) (Box 20)
      Topics include Max Reinhardt, Les Archives Internationales de la danse, the Mexican Morisca, ballet in Russia (including "Inside Informations [sic] about Russian Ballet" by A. A. Ounanian-Ounanoff), and "Warne's Learn to Draw Folders #20: Ballet, Ballroom & Folk Dancing."
  - Posters and broadsides
    - L'Union des Artistes Russes (Map-case 136)
      See also Programs and souvenir booklets: Miscellaneous: U.
    - Miscellaneous, includes Ricardo Linter, Olympia Grand Ballet, Musée Grévin, Revue Chorégraphique de Paris, more (Oversize 1)
  - Programs and souvenir booklets
    - Adolf Bolm Ballet, 1923; 1928,; 1938 (Box 20)
    - Agnes de Mille Dance Theatre, undated (Box 20)
    - American National Ballet Theatre, See Ballet Theatre.
    - La Argentina, 1932; undated (Box 20)
    - Balieff's Chauve-Souris of Moscow, See Theatre de la Chauve-Souris.
    - Ballet Russe, 1911-1912; 1916,; 1919-1920,; 1923,; 1928-1930,; 1933-1934; under Sergei Diaghileff until 1929, then under Colonel Wassily de Basil; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Ballet Russe, 1934-1938; 1954,; undated; under Colonel Wassily de Basil; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Ballet Russe, 1936; under Colonel Wassily de Basil (Oversize 2)
    - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo, 1929-1944; 1953-1960,; undated; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Ballet Theatre (New York), 1940-1943; 1946,; 1950,; 1954-1955,; 1960,; undated; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Ballets de Paris, 1948-1950; undated (Box 22)
    - Bayanihan Philippine Dance Company, undated (Box 22)
      See also Miscellaneous (2), below.
    - Bolshoi Ballet, 1956; 1958,; undated; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Chicago Opera Ballet (Ruth Page), 1950; 1960,; undated; includes performance in Paris (Box 22)
    - Covent Garden, 1938-1939; 1946-1954 (Box 22)
    - Covent Garden, 1954-1958; undated (Box 23)
    - Dancers of Bali, 1957; undated (Box 23)
    - Dunham, Katherine, 1957; undated; also includes a few news clippings (Box 23)
    - Escudero, Vincente, 1932; 1949,; undated (Box 23)
    - Festivals, 1914; 1927-1931,; 1950,; 1960,; undated; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Fokine, Michael, 1935; undated (Box 23)
    - Folies Bergere, 1913-1914; 1924-1925,; 1928,; 1932,; 1937 (Box 23)
    - Grand Ballet de Monte Carlo; New Ballet Russe, 1938-1939; undated (Box 24)
    - Greco, Jose, 1955; undated (Box 24)
    - International Ballet, 1947; 1951-1952,; undated (Box 24)
    - Jooss Ballet, 1933; 1941-1942,; 1945,; undated (Box 24)
    - Lan-Fang, Mei, 1931; undated; includes program from first American tour, with extensive essays on Chinese theatre (Box 24)
    - London's Festival Ballet, 1950-1951; 1958-1959,; 1961; undated; Anton Dolin, Alicia Markova (Box 24)
    - Markova and Dolin, 1936-1938; 1944-1950,; undated (Box 24)
    - Moiseyev Dance Company, 1955; 1958,; 1961,; undated; Russian folk ballet (Box 25)
    - Mordkin Ballet, circa 1920; 1937-1939 (Box 25)
    - National Ballet of Canada, 1951-1957 (Box 25)
    - New York City Ballet, 1951-1957; undated (Box 25)
    - New York City Ballet, 1958-1959 (Oversize 2)
    - Opera Prive de Paris, 1929 (Box 25)
    - Original Ballet Russe, 1940-1941; 1946-1947,; undated (Box 25)
    - Pavlova, Anna, 1911; 1916,; 1921-1922[?],; 1924-1927,; 1930,; undated (Box 25)
    - Pavlova, Anna, 1931-1937; 1956,; undated (Box 26)
    - Polish Ballet, 1937; 1959 (Box 26)
    - Reinhardt, Max, 1924; 1938 (Box 26)
      See also Pamphlets: Miscellaneous (2), above.
    - Royal Ballet (Great Britain), 1960-1961 (Box 26)
    - Royal Danish Ballet, 1939; 1950[?],; 1956-1957 (Box 26)
    - Rubenstein. Ida, 1912; 1920,; 1929; includes a few newspaper clippings (Box 26)
    - Sadler's Wells Ballet, 1944-1956; undated; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Shankar, Uday, 1932; 1937-1938,; 1950 (Box 27)
    - Shawn, Ted and St. Denis, Ruth, circa 1915; 1924,; 1927,; 1939,; 1944,; 1949,; 1952-1956,; undated; includes The Denishawn Dancers, Shawn and His Men Dancers, Jacob's Pillow Dance Festival (Box 27)
    - Slavenska, Mia, 1952-1954; includes Slavenska Franklin Ballet, Ballet Variante, Slavenska Tihmar and Company (Box 27)
    - Southern Ballet, 1953-1959; includes Southern Ballet of Atlanta (Box 27)
    - Theatre de la Chauve-Souris, 1921-1924; includes Balieff's Chauve-Souris of Moscow (Box 27)
    - Theatre des Champs-Elysees, 1913; 1933,; 1946,; 1949-1951,; 1958,; undated; includes Saison Russe, Ballets Portugais, Ballets de Champs-Élysées, various ballet companies of the Marquis de Cuevas (Box 27)
    - Theatre des Champs-Elysees, 1946 (Oversize 2)
    - Theatre National de l'Opera (Paris), 1923; 1948,; undated (Box 27)
    - Theatre National de l'Opera (Paris), 1938 (Oversize 2)
    - Vashi, Nataraj, 1947; undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous companies, venues and performers, A-Z
      - A, Alexandra Theatre (Birmingham), Académie Nationale de Musique et de Danse, (Carmen) Amaya (Box 28)
      - B, Bal de la Grand Ourse, (Alexandra) Balachova, Ballet for America, Ballet de l'Amérique Latine, Ballets Basques de Biarritz, Ballet Caravan, Ballet Carnival, Ballet Celeste, Ballet de la Ciudad de México, Ballet Indien, Ballet Mexicano, Ballet Rambert, Ballet Society, Le Ballet-Theatre Français, Ballets Espagnols, Ballets de l'Opera de Paris, Ballets Suédois, (Alfonso) Benavides, (Henry) Bernstein, Borovansky Ballet; 3 folders (Box 28)
      - B, oversize, Ballet de Cuba, Belgium ( Les Fleurs and Les Mouchoirs) (Oversize 2)
      - C, (Fernande) Cabanel, (Walter) Camryn, Casino de Paris, (Janine) Charrat, Chicago Symphony Orchestra, (Francisco) Clerico (very interesting item - program dating from 1821 Milan), (Jan) Cobel (Polish ballets), (Janet) Collins, Conferences Charles Cros, Connecticut Pops (Box 28)
      - D, E, F, G, Dance Theater Berlin, (Lycette) Darsonval, De Quevao[?], (Isadora) Duncan, (Raymond) Duncan, Edinburgh International Festival of Music and Drama, Ensemble of the Red Army, (Vicente) Escudero, Foxhole Ballet, Georgian State Dance Company, (José) Greco, The Grand Concert (film version of Borodin's Prince Igor) (Box 28)
      - G, oversize, (Martha) Graham (Oversize 2)
      - J, K, June Taylor Dancers, Jushny's Theater, Kabuki dancers, Kanellos Greek Festival, (Thamar) Karsavina, (Leo) Kehl, Kirsova Australian Ballet (book of drawings and sketches), (Boris) Kniaseff, det Kongelige Teater (Box 28)
      - L, Latin Quarter, Leningrad-Kirov Ballet, (Serge) Lifar (including an art catalog), (Lydia) Lopokova, Los Angeles Grand Opera, Los Angeles Music Guild (Box 29)
      - L, oversize, London Philharmonic ( The Nutcracker) (Oversize 2)
      - M, Manhattan Opera House, Mata and Hari and Company, Mayfair School of Dancing, Metropolitan Opera House (benefit for Widowed Mothers Fund Association), (Darius) Milhaud (premier of his David), Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra, Moliere ("Le Bourgeouis Gentilhomme"), (Mikhail) Mordkin, Moscow Art Theatre Musical Studio, Moscow State Symphony, Moulin Rouge, Music Hall (Box 29)
      - N, Nashville Ballet Society, National Ballet of Lithuania, National Ballet Theatre of Finland, New Centyry Theatre, New York World's Fair 1940, (Doris) Niles et Serge Leslie, Nrityalayam, Offenbach ( Tales of Hoffman), Oklahoma!, L'Opera de Paris (Box 29)
      - O, Palace aux Femmes, Palais du Chaillot, Paris Opera Ballet, Pasadena Regional Ballet, (Roland) Petit, Piccolo Teatro di Milano (Box 29)
      - R, Radio City Music Hall, Ram Gopal, (Shanta) Rao and her Dancers of India, The Red Shoes, (Jerome) Robbins' Ballets: USA, (Billy) Rose's Show of Shows, Royal Academy of Dancing, Royal Winnipeg Ballet of Canada, Russian Festival (Box 29)
      - R, oversize, (Jerome) Robbins; Royal Opera Covent Garden (Oversize 2)
      - S, (Clotilde and Alexandre) Sakharoff, San Francisco Civic Ballet, San Francisco Russian Opera and Ballet Association, Santa Fe Opera, (Trudi) Schoop and her Comic Ballet, Shakespeare Memorial Theatre, Soviet Dancers in Britain, Soviet Opera Stars, Soviet Theatre, Stone-Camryn Ballet, (Steffy) Stahl (Box 29)
      - S, oversize, Scheherezade (circa 1930, in French with very nice tipped-in color illustrations) (Oversize 2)
      - T, Takarazuka Dance Theatre, Texas Christian University Fine Arts Ballet, Teatro Classico della Repubblica Popolare di Cina, Teatro Odeon, Teatro de la Opera, Theatre d'Art du Ballet, Theatre du Chatelet, Theatre Femina, Theatre de Monte Carlo, Theatre Royal (Box 30)
      - T, oversize, Teatro Municipal (Oversize 2)
      - U, oversize, L'Union des Artistes Russes (several items) (Oversize 2)
        See also Programs and broadsides: L'Union des Artistes Russes, above.
      - V, Z, (Andre) Van Damme, Vecheslova and Chabukani, Vienna Ballet, Vic-Wells Ballet, Ziegfeld Follies (Box 30)
      - Russian language, miscellaneous (Box 30)
  - Scripts
    - Miscellaneous, "Joint Owners in Spain" by Alice Brown (1913); "A Russian Honeymoon" by Mrs. Burton Harrison (1911) (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous (1), 2 folders (Box 30)
    Items include programs, newsletters, photocopy of copyright agreement for Arbeau's Orchesography, numerous items relating to painter Eugene Berman, and large posters for a performance by De Ballet do Rio de Janeiro.
  - Miscellaneous (2), 3 folders (Box 31)
    Items include programs, exhibit announcements and invitations, calling cards, postcards, newsletters, a Stravinsky bibliography, a press folder for Bayanihan Philippine Dance Company, numerous items relating to Perry Rawson and roller skating, a calendar illustrated with dance-related photographs, line drawings and cartoons, 1951 Annual Guide to Music and Musicians in Los Angeles, membership directory for Chicago National Association of Dance Masters, and book jackets.
  - Miscellaneous (3) (Oversize 2)
    Reproductions of pages in French with text and illustrations regarding a "Parodie de Giselle ou les Willis, ballet en deux actes"; "Grandmother's Minuet"; reproductions of paintings from Museum of Modern Art; advertising brochure for book on Canaletto
- Subject files
  - Bibliographies and lists, printed, handwritten, typescript in English, French and Russian; includes bibliographies, "want lists" for books, lists of dancers, etc.; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Kamin Dance Bookshop
    See also Photographs: General: Kamin Dance Bookshop and Printed material: Kamin Dance Bookshop.
    - Promotional albums, 2 volumes (Oversize 4)
      Albums contain hundreds of press releases, mimeo notices, printed and engraved cards fro reading and discussions (1930-1940), as well as many small leaflets for books that were carried in the Kamin Dance Bookshop but not published by Kamin. There are also numerous mimeographed letters to librarians about books published and carried by the bookshop. Some pages have pencilled notes.
    - Miscellaneous, printed material, photo of storefront, notebook, miscellany (Box 31)
  - Kamin Publishers
    - Forms and form letters, contracts, offer forms, boilerplate letters, etc. (Box 31)
    - Scrapbook, 1939-1955; reviews, letters of appreciation, clippings, etc. (Box 31)
  - Licht, Michel, notes, lists (Box 31)
  - Middle East, notes, clippings, lists, printed material (Box 31)
  - Military newspaper, correspondence about publication of weekly newspaper, mockup of layout (Box 31)
- Writings
  - By Kamin
    - Both Sides, Sep 1936; edited by Kamin (Box 32)
    - Notebooks, 1943-1945 (Box 32)
    - Notes, war years, 1943-1945; loose sheets, fragments, brief notes, etc., most undated but evidently from war years (Box 32)
    - "Rascals", handwritten notes for unidentified piece of writing (Box 32)
    - St. Elmo by Augusta J. Evans, notes, possibly for essay or book review (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous, notes, handwritten fragments, scraps, unnumbered pages, etc.; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - By Kamin, probably
    - Dance, topics include "The library for the dancer"; a proposed table of contents for a book on dance; "A proposal for the establishment of a permanent dance theatre devoted to the development of American ballet"; reviews of several books by Tomaz Ribas (Box 32)
    - Politics, topics include the arts in exile, U.S. attitude towards Soviet-influenced countries, Polish Jews, Morccan Jews, what American should know about North Africa, the Phalangist movement in France, the Nationalist movement in the Arab world, and assorted fragments (Box 32)
    - World War II, topics include the black market, observations on London, Mussolini's Italy, public relations, concentration camps in North Africa, and how to get underground news into occupied countries (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous, notes and fragments on the publishing industry, integrated folk art, proposal for an international current events journal, Theodore Komisarjevsky, notes to printer regarding errata in unidentified book (Box 32)
  - By Sally Katz Kamin
    - D. H. Lawrence: An appreciation, handwritten manuscript (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous, notes, fragments, etc. (Box 32)
  - By others
    - —, Larry, 1920-1921; poems addressed to Sally Kamin; handwritten, some with accompanying notes (Box 32)
    - Alanova, Kira, Arabesque, A Romance of the Ballet, circa 1937; summary of "novel to be published Spring, 1938"; typescript (Box 32)
    - Armstrong, Ronald, 1956-1958; extensive correspondence; typescript of chapter on Sandoz from Armstrong's unpublished memoirs; photographs of Sandoz; typescript of preface to Sandoz' On the Pleasures of Mexico (Box 33)
    - Belknap, Riginald R. (Rear Admiral), "Why wars come", 1956-1958; essay; typescript (Box 33)
    - Bolm, Adolf, 1941; undated (Box 33)
      Six typescript items: (1) Interview of Isabel Morse Jones with Adolf Bolm; (2) Tribute to Anna Pavlova; (3) excerpt of play about Maria Taglioni, with accompanying rejection note from MGM Studios; (4) article about Bolm by Mark Turbyfill; (5) spoken prologue and summary for production of Prokofiev's Peter and the Wolf, with choreography by Bolm; (6) Transcript of interview of Bolm by Irving Deakin
    - Chatterjee, Santosh, Bharata Nat am: the Dance of Gesture, 1948; outline for book; typescript with cover letter (Box 33)
    - Cinquabre, Pierre, The dance among the African black race, preface to book, in English and French; typescript (Box 33)
    - Cooke, Marjorie Benton, The Case of Sophronia, Scene I; typescript carbon (Box 33)
    - Dekobra, Maurice, Uranium 235: A Ballet in Two Scenes, 1945; ballet scenario; typescript carbon (Box 33)
    - Engel, Leonard, [untitled book on American politics], book proposal, lists Theodore Thorner and Martin Kamin as co-authors (Box 33)
    - Giaeosa, —, Sacred Ground, excerpt of play; typescript carbon (Box 33)
    - Halter, Dolores, "Suggested plans for organization and administration of Akron Civic Ballet Company", essay; typescript carbon (Box 33)
    - Hanna, Robert, Dainishah, play; typescript (Box 33)
    - Kay, Lisan, "Destiny and I meet Nimura", biographical sketch of dancer, teacher, and choreographer Yeichi Nimura; typescript (Box 33)
    - Kerr, Geoffrey, Mabel and Jane, episode 1, "The Tickets" (Box 33)
    - Krasovskaja, V., "The decay of ballet in the West", 1950; essay; typescript carbon with additional handwritten notes possible by Sally Kamin (Box 33)
    - Massaguer, Conrado, The Life and Times of Massaguer, biographical introduction, scattered sections containing his views of various people such as Will Rogers and André Maurois; typescript carbon (Box 33)
    - McPhee, Conn, The Ballinese Shadow Play, additions and changes to book, with accompanying cover letter to Kamin; typescript (Box 33)
    - Morgan, Wehlen, "Dance, spinach, collards and mustard greens", essay; typescript (Box 33)
    - Moskowitz[?], Nicholas, poems, each one signed; typescript (Box 33)
    - Nijinsky, Kira, [untitled on sound, color and movement, "keyrartnik"], essay; typescript carbon with hand-colored illustrations (Box 33)
    - Parker, Louise, A Minuet, partial script of play; typescript carbon and clipped printed pages (Box 33)
    - Potapov, Vladimir, "The quality of Galina Ulanova's dancing", essay; typescript (Box 33)